<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Floating</title>
    <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_" />
    <updated>2024-03-18T18:03:11-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Floating Further</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/floating-further.html"/>
        <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/floating-further.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-12T13:47:07-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    After visiting each obstacle, you can't help but wonder which you felt aligned with you the most. The shooting so-called stars that overwhelmed&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>After visiting each obstacle, you can't help but wonder which you felt aligned with you the most. The shooting so-called stars that overwhelmed you, the burnt-out star, or the sucking black hole. All felt too familiar. <br><br>Everyone feels like they're floating at a certain point in their lives. Everyone feels lost at a certain point, not sure where they stand in life. Time just seems to fly, people seeming to run while you're walking. Comparing yourself to others is what you can't help to do, wondering why you're behind while they're all so ahead. Feeling like you've been in the dark for too long, like you can't feel that fire in you no longer.</p>
<p>People may feel burnt out, worn out from all the stress that life has to offer. People may feel extremely anxious, constantly worried about the future and what to make of it. People may have prolonged sadness, feeling like they entered a deep hole that they can never get out of. </p>
<p>There's always a place you can land, though. A place where you can feel like you can get back up on your feet and feel safe. A place you can call home, whether it is a physical place, imagined place, or people. There is always a way out no matter where you are in life. As long as you keep on going, even if it feels like you're floating nowhere, you'll reach the ground someday. And you'll come back stronger, fired up, ready to face life once again.</p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/welcome-d.html" class="button">Home</a>  <a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/about.html" class="button">About the Project</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Supernova</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/burnout.html"/>
        <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/burnout.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-12T13:57:05-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Welcome to the Supernova, or more, "the Burnt Out Star." The supernova occurs when a star is dying, with it's fire inside fading&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em>Welcome to the Supernova, or more, "the Burnt Out Star." The supernova occurs when a star is dying, with it's fire inside fading and dimming as time passes until it will explode. As you float close to the star, you notice your body feeling heavier. You connect with the star.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="align-center">Burnout</h2>
<p>The feeling of burnout is a common feeling amongst all of us, especially as students. Often times we wonder, "How did I become like this? I was so strongheaded and organized not too long ago, what's wrong with me?" It occurs after a prolonged amount of stress that gets to the point of interfering with our ability to do daily tasks.</p>
<h2 class="align-center">Common signs of Burnout are:</h2>
<p>As per Malvern Behavioral Health, Jerry Kosmin refers to these signs of burnout:</p>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0E1326; padding: 10px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 107.953px;">
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 107.953px;">Exhaustion</td>
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 107.953px;">Even with a lot of sleep, you feel as if you can't go about with your day without feeling fatigue.</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 79.1562px;">Lack of Motivation and Interest</td>
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 79.1562px;">You feel diminished feelings of doing daily tasks, or things you used to enjoy.</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 136.75px;">
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 136.75px;">Lack of Creativity and Concentration</td>
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 136.75px;">With fatigue comes a decrease in our creative abilities, leading to prolongued procrastination. You feel unable to feel organized or motivated to do work.</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 136.75px;">
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 136.75px;">Increased Irritability</td>
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 136.75px;">You get to the point where you get mad at yourself for being incapable of doing what you normally were able to do. It's not your fault, but you feel as it is. </td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 165.547px;">
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 165.547px;">Frequent Illnesses</td>
<td style="width: 50.0713%; height: 165.547px;">After prolonged stress and overdoing yourself, your body will start to wear out and tell you it needs a break. Not taking a break and pushing yourself will wear you out even further.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>With increased stress is a higher toll on your body, leading to high cortisol (stress hormone) levels, high blood pressure, and ultimately fatigue. Most common factors that contribute to such stress in students is comparing ourselves to other people, immense workloads, neverending deadlines, and feelings of loneliness.  Anxiety is all over your mind, you feel susceptible to be depressed. You can't help but wonder if you're even doing the right thing.</p>
<p class="msg--info">Did you know loneliness is as deadly as smoking 15 cigarettes a day?</p>
<h2 class="align-center">There is such a thing as "good stress" and "bad stress"</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/stress-model.jpeg" alt="Good Stress - Bad Stress Model" width="453" height="350" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-md.jpeg 768w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/5/responsive/stress-model-2xl.jpeg 1600w">
<figcaption >Lower amounts of stress have better effects compared to high amounts of stress.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Stress in itself is not a bad thing. It is a part of our daily lives and what can act as a motivating factor to keep us going. Smaller levels of stress are what allow us to stay focused and feel the need to reach our goals.</p>
<p>Excessive amounts of stress, however, is what can cause a strain on our bodies. Being exposed to too much stress will lead to mental, physical, emotional breakdowns which can lead to burn out. So don't be afraid to experience stress, but don't let stress overtake your entire life.</p>
<h2 class="align-center">Strategies to Cope</h2>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0E1326; padding: 10px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;"><strong>Strategies</strong></td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Go Outside! Get Some Fresh Air</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Go out for a breather and feel the Vitamin D. Take a walk or go out and exercise so you can keep your body up and going, firing it up. Seeing green every so often can make your mind relax.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Remind Yourself to Take Your Own Pace</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Go out for a breather and feel the Vitamin D. Take a walk or go out and exercise so you can keep your body up and going, firing it up. Seeing green every so often can make your mind relax.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Reach Out to Your Close Circle</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Ask for help when you need! Your friends and family are there to support you, and there is no shame in asking for help. Small words of encouragement can spring you back up to action. </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p><em>A star dies due to exhausting itself of its hydrogen levels, ultimately not able to fuel itself no longer. With a little bit of extra fire and help from others, maybe the star could be brought back again. Just as you can.</em></p>
<p class="align-center"><span style="color: #236fa1;"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/anxiety.html" class="button">Continue -&gt;</a></span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Black Hole</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/depression.html"/>
        <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/depression.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-18T18:01:58-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You're floating further and further until you feel something pulling you down. Your body heavy, your body getting pulled in. You look up&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em>You're floating further and further until you feel so</em><em>mething pulling you down. Your body heavy, your body getting pulled in. You look up to notice it's a black hole. A big one. Time seems to slow, you see clocks flying past. You close your eyes and take a deep breathe in. You let it take you in.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="align-center">Depression</h2>
<p>According to the World Health Organization, depression is "persistent sadness and a lack of interest or pleasure from previously rewarding or enjoyable activities,” and globally, about 5% of adults suffer from depression."</p>
<p>Depression has become a common term to refer to prolonged sadness in media, but that in itself may undermine the reality of those who experience depression as a condition. There are different types of depression such as major depression, seasonal affective disorder, and bipolar disorder. Each has its own set of longetivity and extent of symptoms. It is important to see depression as a condition that can range from different extremities, so not all people will look exactly the same.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/black-hole.png" alt="Bunny feeling down, black hole drawing it in." width="404" height="344" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-xs.png 300w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-sm.png 480w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-md.png 768w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-lg.png 1024w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-xl.png 1360w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/4/responsive/black-hole-2xl.png 1600w"></figure>
<h2 class="align-center">Common Symptoms</h2>
<p>According to the National Institute of Mental Health, symptoms of depression include (but not all):</p>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0E1326; padding: 10px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Persistent sad, anxious, "empty" mood</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Feeling hopeless or pessimistic</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Feelings of irritability, frustration, restelessness</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Lost of Interest in what you normally enjoyed (hobbies, activities)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Decreased energy, fatiugue, inability to concentrate or remember</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Change in appetite</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Physical aches</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">Perceived slower sense of time</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 class="align-center">Statistics</h2>
<p>Data from the American College Health Association (ACHA) shows t27% of college students noted having depression in 2022, with 78% reporting that they reached out to a healthcare professional. A major factor that contributed to this statistic was COVID, which began in 2020 and is ongoing today. Having to be isolated for so long without social support has taken a toll on mental health, especially among young adults.</p>
<h2 class="align-center">Common Strategies to Cope</h2>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0E1326; padding: 10px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Eat healthy, nutritious food</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Exercise daily, go outside for fresh air</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Reach out to your close circle, spend time with loved ones</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Reach out to a professional in regards to medication</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p><em>Inside the black hole, you feel as if you're being stretched to pieces. You feel you can't escape until a hand reaches out to you. You immediately grab it and you're pulled out. Who was your savior? It's unclear, as no one is around as you're back into space, floating once again. Filled with panic, you take a deep breathe in and calm your body. You float further once again.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="align-center"><span style="color: #236fa1;"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/anxiety.html" class="button"> &lt;- Go Back </a>              <a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/floating-further.html" class="button">Continue -&gt;</a></span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Shooting Stars</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/anxiety.html"/>
        <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/anxiety.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-18T18:03:11-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You float further and see what seems to be shooting stars. You go closer, only to find that they are actually meteors shooting&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="align-left"><em>You float further and see what seems to be shooting stars. You go closer, only to find that they are actually meteors shooting across. Each burning, each gaining speed. Your curiousity overtakes you, and you land on top of one of the meteors.</em></p>
<p class="align-left"><em>The meteor is burning, it overwhelms you. There's too many around you. All burning up, all gaining speed. You jump off, hoping there aren't more. But it doesn't stop. It just keeps going, shaking up your body.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="align-center">Anxiety</h2>
<p>Anxiety is very common to experience, and it comes with overwhelming thoughts. Anxiety comes in many different forms, which include social anxiety, panic, phobias, etc. </p>
<p>Anxiety is normal. It is something we all experience that goes hand-in-hand with our stress. Just as stress in moderate levels is fine, anxiety in moderate levels is fine. It is what keeps us anticipating and prepared. Of course, too much of it is not good for our bodies, which can overwhelm us and feel like too much.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><em><img loading="lazy"  src="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/shooting-stars.png" alt="Bunny with a lot of intrusive thoughts, bunch of shooting stars surrounding." width="476" height="374" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-xs.png 300w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-sm.png 480w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-md.png 768w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-lg.png 1024w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-xl.png 1360w ,https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/media/posts/3/responsive/shooting-stars-2xl.png 1600w"></figure></em></p>
<h2 class="align-center">Common Symptoms</h2>
<p>According to the World Health Organization, common symptoms are:</p>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0E1326; padding: 10px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 100%; height: 50.3594px;">trouble concentrating/making decisions</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 100%; height: 50.3594px;">feeling irritable, tense, or restless</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 100%; height: 50.3594px;">experiencing nausea or abdominal distress</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 100%; height: 50.3594px;">having heart palpitations</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 100%; height: 50.3594px;">
<p>sweating, trembling, shaking</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">
<p>trouble sleeping</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 100%;">
<p>sense of impending danger or panic</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>*It is extremely important to not self-diagnose yourself. It is popular for social media posts to engage their audience by asking if you "relate to these symptoms" and diagnose you with a certain condition. Those that are not clinically anxious can also experience similar symptoms, like trouble making decisions.  In order to confirm, make sure to reach out to a professional.*</em></p>
<h2 class="align-center">Statistics</h2>
<p>Data from the American College Health Association (ACHA) shows that 35% of college students noted being diagnosed with anxiety in 2022, with 77% reaching out to healthcare professionals.</p>
<p>A major factor that contributed to this statistic was COVID, which began in 2020 and is ongoing today. Having to be isolated for so long without social support has taken a toll on mental health, especially among young adults. In addition, the constant stress of feeling the need to predict the future as college students is a major factor, as college students feel the need to figure their life out by the time they graduate. It is important to remember that it is okay to be behind, and we shouldn't expect ourselves to make such important decisions. Our brains do not fully develop until we are 25 years old, so as college students it's okay to make mistakes and not know what we are doing.</p>
<h2 class="align-center">Common Strategies to Cope</h2>
<table style="border: 2px solid #0e1326; padding: 10px; width: 100%; height: 303.156px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50.8594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.8594px;">Self Care (exercise, eat healthy, go outside)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;"><a href="https://www.priorygroup.com/blog/breathing-exercises-for-anxiety" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Breathing Exercises (click to see methods)</a></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Reach out to loved ones and share your thoughts</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Ground yourself in what's real and what's possible</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 99.8575%; height: 50.3594px;">Reach out to a healthcare professional if it's too much</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p><em>After a few minutes, there is finally an end to this storm of shooting "stars." What seemed to be endless actually had an end, and you are able to relax. We don't know when this storm will begin again, but there is safety knowing you are okay now. Your body calms down, and you shake no longer. You decide to float further.</em></p>
<p class="align-center"><span style="color: #236fa1;"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/burnout.html" class="button"> &lt;- Back </a>              <a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/depression.html" class="button">Continue -&gt;</a></span></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Welcome to Floating</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Hwang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/welcome-d.html"/>
        <id>https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/welcome-d.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-12T14:52:32-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As you float across time and space, you'll come across different obstacles. Each obstacle will bring different feelings. Each a common entity amongst&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="align-center">As you float across time and space, you'll come across different obstacles. Each obstacle will bring different feelings. Each a common entity amongst all of us. Venture into each and see where you land. </p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/burnout.html" class="button" style="background-color: #6a81b8; color: #f8f8f1;">The Supernova </a>   <a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/anxiety.html" class="button" style="background-color: #6a81b8; color: #f8f8f1;">Shooting Comets</a>  <a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/depression.html" class="button" style="background-color: #6a81b8; color: #f8f8f1;">The Black Hole</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://shwang02.github.io/floating_/about.html" class="button">About the Project</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
